<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="bangalore_palace">At a distance of 4 km from Bangalore City Railway Station, Bangalore Place is situated in the heart of Bangalore city, near Sadashiv Nagar. Bangalore Place is one of the best palaces in South India. This is one of the best places to visit in Bangalore city.
    The Palace was first built by Rev. J. Garrett, who was the first Principal of the Central High School in Bangalore, now known as Central College. Spread over an area of 454 acres, the construction of the palace was started in 1862 and completed in 1944. In 1887, it was bought by the then Maharaja of Mysore Chamarajendra Wodeyar X.
    During a visit to England, Chamaraja Wodeyar was inspired by the Windsor Castle in London and along similar lines he built this palace in Tudor style. The Palace is famous for its elegantly carved woodwork. The interiors have awesome floral motifs, cornices, mouldings and relief paintings on its ceilings. Gothic windows, fortified towers, battlements and turrets lend a great degree of magnificence to the Bangalore Palace. There are 35 rooms in the palace, along with a manual lift. The inner walls of the palace are also decorated with paintings from 19th century.
    The palace has a large open square courtyard with granite seats, a ballroom, the Durbar hall along with a number of paintings of Raja Ravi Varma, a dining table of the Diwan of Mysore, Sir Mirza Ismail, among the others. The Wodeyars were believed to be great hunters, and Jayachamaraja Wodeyar was considered to have hunted around 300 tigers and several elephants. One such elephant head is mounted at the entrance of the palace. Stools made of elephant feet, vases of the elephant trunk, and trophies of elephant hunting are displayed in the palace.
    Once the residence of the Wodeyars, it now serves as the venue for various concerts, exhibitions and cultural programs held in the city. Presently, Bangalore Palace is under the ownership of the descendant of the Mysore Royal Family, Srikanta Datta Narasimharaja Wodeyar. He opened the palace in 2005 for public viewing. The palace has recently undergone a renovation.
    Entry Fee: Rs. 225 for Indians and Rs. 450 for foreigners, still camera: Rs. 675, Video Camera: Rs.1000 and Mobile Camera: Rs.100.
    Timings: 10 AM to 5:30 PM.
    </string>

    <string name="tipu_sulthans_fort">At a distance of 3 km from Bangalore City Railway Station, Tipu Sultan\'s Palace or Tipu\'s Summer Palace is situated near the Tipu\'s Fort at Albert Victor Road. This palace stands as one of the notable Islamic buildings and an important landmark in the city of Bangalore. This was used as a summer retreat by the Sultan, who lovingly called it the Rash-e-Jannat meaning Envy of Haven.
        Hyder Ali started the construction of the palace within the walls of the Bangalore Fort and it was completed by Tipu Sultan in 1791. Used as a summer retreat, the structure is similar to the Daria Daulat palace of Srirangapatnam. After Tipu Sultan\'s death in the Fourth Anglo-Mysore War, the British Administration used the palace for its Secretariat before moving to Attara Kacheri in 1868. 
        The Summer Palace is an example of Indo-Islamic architecture. The entire palace is built of teak wood, mortar, stone and plaster. It is laid on a stone plinth. The structure is two-storied and is supported by wooden pillars that rest on the stone base. The exquisitely carved pillars support giant wooden beams that hold the structure. It is believed that Tipu Sultan used to conduct his durbar from the upper floor of the palace. The upper chambers and balconies can be accessed by four staircases with the central portion being a large hall that leads to four smaller rooms. These rooms are considered to be women\'s quarters. Beautiful floral motifs enhance the walls and the ceilings of the palace.
        The palace now houses a small museum showcasing various achievements of Tipu Sultan and his administration. There are several portraits of the people and places of that time. Besides the delicate carving and paintings, it houses an art gallery of nearly a thousand historical photos and artifacts of Hyder Ali, Tipu Sultan and other famous personalities. There is a replica of Tipu's Tiger, which is in the Victoria and Albert Museum in London. Tipu Sultan's clothes and his crown are present in silver and gold pedestals.
        The site also holds a painting of grand throne visualized by Tipu Sultan himself. Coated with gold sheets and stuck with precious emerald stones, Tipu had vowed never to use it until he completely defeated the English Army. After Tipu Sultan's death, the British dismantled the throne and auctioned its parts. Museum is maintained and managed by the Archaeological Survey of India.
        Entry Fee: Rs.5 for Indians and Rs.100 for foreigners. Photography is allowed and there is no special fee for camera.
        Timings: 10 AM to 6 PM from Monday to Saturday. Closed on Sundays.
    </string>

    <string name="avani">At a distance of 30 km from Kolar and 98.5 km from Bangalore City Junction, Avani is a small village in Kolar district of Karnataka. Avani is renowned for housing varied ancient temples. It is also a popular location for rock climbing. It is also an important historical sites and a popular sightseeing spot around Bangalore.
        The village of Avani received a prominent place mainly due to the legends associated with it. According to mythology, goddess Sita gave birth to her twin children Lava-Kusha at Avani. It is also said that the war between Lord Rama and his sons Lava and Kusha took place in this village. As per the local belief, sage Valmiki, the author of the epic Ramayana was residing here during the period of Ramayana.
        Another legend has it that when Sri Narasimha Bharati IV of the Sringeri Sharada Peetham was on his sancharas\', he camped here for a few days. During his stay in Avani, he discovered an idol of Goddess Sharada. The idol was in standing posture flanked by Adi Shankaracharya with Sri Chakra. He established a new Mutt, which is presently known as Avani Sringeri Jagadguru Shankaracharya Sharada Peetham. 
        Avani also houses a Sita temple situated on a hill. This temple is one of the few temples dedicated to Sita Devi in India. This temple has the idols of Sita Devi and Parvati Devi. This is considered the place where Sita Devi went into ground after handing over Lava and Kusha to Rama.
        Avani also has ancient temples known as the Ramalingeshwara, Lakshmaneshwara, Bharateshwara and Shatrugneshwara, built by the Nolamba rulers in 10th century. According to legend, Rama was performing Ashwamedha Yaga when his Horse was tied up by Lava and Kusha. Even after repeated requests by Lakshmana, Bharatha, Shatrugna and others, they did not free the Horse and fight took place between them. When everyone lost to Lava and Kusha, Rama himself turned up and had to fight. Later this was disrupted by Sita. This is a sin since the fight was between father and the sons and other relatives. This was the reason Valmiki installed the Lingas for papa pariharam. The entire compound comes under the purview of the Archaeological Department and is well maintained.
        Maha Shivaratri and Ramalingeshwara rathostava are the famous festivals that are celebrated with great pomp and fervor here. 
    </string>

    <string name="tipu_fort">At a distance of 3 Kms from Bangalore City Railway Station, The Tipu\'s Fort is set in the heart of the Bangalore city opposite to the city market. The fort is originally constructed using mud and brick by Kempe Gowda in 1537 AD. Later an extension was made by Chikkadevaraya Wodeyar of Mysore and again the structure was later demolished and reconstructed by Haider Ali and his son Tipu Sultan in the 18th century.
        The fort is a two-storied wooden structure, carved out of teakwood with decorated pillars, concave arches and balconies. Today the fort houses a museum adorned with ancient artifacts from Hyder Ali  Tipu's regime. The fort is noted for its beautifully carved arches in Islamic style and for the well-preserved temple dedicate to Lord Ganesh. Most part of the fort is in ruins.
        Timings: 10 AM to 6 PM. Closed on Sundays. </string>

    <string name="high_court">At a distance of 3.5 Kms from Bangalore City Railway Station, Attara Kacheri is a building housing the High Court of Karnataka state. Situated opposite to Vidhana Soudha, the Attara Kacheri is a beautiful 19th century stone structure. One of the major attractions of the Attara Kacheri is its Gothic Style of architecture.
        It is a two-storied building, built in the European classical style. Built with red stone, it serves as the perfect contrast to the white columned building of Vidhana Soudha. Attara Kacheri was built under the reign of Tipu Sultan, the Emperor of Mysore. He named the building as Attara Kacheri, meaning eighteen offices or departments. This was completed in 1864 and housed the Public Offices from 1868 until 1956. These were later moved to the Vidhana Soudha, and this building became the high court. On the ceiling of its Central Hall is a Portrait of Sir Mark Cubbon, Commissioner of Mysore from 1834 to 1861. Behind the building is a statue of him by Baron Marochetti.
    </string>
</resources>