<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="vish_ind">At a distance of 5 km from Bangalore City Railway Station, Visweswaraiah Industrial and Technological Museum (VITM) is located on Kasturba road in the surroundings of Cubbon Park. It was established as a tribute to Sir M Visweswaraiah, a great civil engineer. This is one of the best science museums in India and one of the best places to visit in Bangalore city, especially for children.
        The museum occupies an area of 4000 sq. m, housing various industrial products and engines, which were opened by Sri Pandit Jawaharlal Nehru in 1962. The first gallery set up at VITM on the theme Electricity was opened to the public in 1965. An airplane and a steam engine are displayed in its compound. 
        VITM has 7 permanent exhibition galleries titled Engine Hall, Fun Science, Electro technic, Space - Emerging Technology in the Service of Mankind, Biotechnological Revolution, BEL Hall of Electronics and Children Science. The Engine Hall exhibits engines of various automobiles, machines used in industry, a jet aircraft engine and other mechanical devices. The Electro Technic Gallery contains interactive electrical exhibits which work on the basic principles of electricity, electronics and communication. The Fun Science gallery exhibits the sciences of sound, optics, fluids and perception.
        The Space Gallery is about rocket science and the history of space exploration. Biotechnology hall has exhibits on basics of Biotechnology and its applications. The Dinosaur alive has a moving replica of a Spinosaurus. The BEL Hall of Electronics has interesting exhibits on Electronics. There is a giant piano over which children can dance to play music. A pin-wall helps the children make the impression of their body parts on it. There is a virtual game area, where children can play music using virtual instruments. 
        A new 3D theater is open to the public now which showcases interesting films on deep sea diving and brain are screened here. The museum also conducts a mini-planetarium show called Taramandal at regular intervals. This is the only museum in the world other than the Smithsonian Institutions in the US, to have a full scale replica of the 1903 flyer of Wright brothers. 
        The museum has Mobile Science Exhibition with 24 participatory exhibits mounted on a bus. Launched in the year 1970, the Mobile Science Exhibition travels through the length and breadth of the whole of South India. 
        Entry Fee: General Visitors: Rs.40, 3D show: Rs.25, Taramandal: Rs.10, SDL (Science Demonstration Lecture): Rs.10 and SOS (Science on a Sphere): Rs.25. There is a special fee for school children.
        Timings: 10 AM to 6 PM all days except Ganesh Chathurthi and Diwali.
    </string>

    <string name="gov_mus">At a distance of 4 Kms from Bangalore City Railway Station, The Karnataka Government Museum is located at the Kasturba Gandhi Road, quite near to the Cubbon Park. Established in 1886, it is one of the oldest museums in India. It is also known as State Archeological Museum. With great collection of artifacts, it\'s one of the ideal places to visit in Bangalore for history art lovers.
        There are 18 galleries showcasing a rich collection of coins, art and relics from the Mohenjodaro, Halebid and Vijayanagara. It also houses the relics dating back to 5000 years. The painting gallery includes beautiful and rare paintings in Mysore and Tanjore style and also paintings from Rajasthani and Pahari schools. The museum also preserves antiques that date back to the civilization of Harappa and Mohenjodaro. Among the other artifacts on display, ivory carvings, inlay work, sandal-wood caskets are highly appreciated.
        Timings: 10 AM to 5 PM. Closed on Wednesdays and public holidays.
        Entry Fee: Rs. 10 for Adults Rs. 5 for Children
    </string>

    <string name="venkatappa">At a distance of 4 Kms from Bangalore City Railway Station, The Venkatappa Art Gallery is situated in the Karnataka Government Museum. The Art Gallery is comprised of two floors and displays 600 paintings. It houses some of the exclusive collections of scenic displays and also a must visit place in Bangalore for art lovers.
        Venkatappa Art Gallery, as the name suggests has an exhibition of the great works of the famous artist K. Venkatappa. Some of the great works of the painter that one can see in the gallery include scenic view of the lake of Ooty, Nilgiri Mountains at Kodaikanal, sunrise of Ooty and so on. Works of artists like MF Hussain, Vasudev, Hanumaiah, Hariram, Rekha Rao etc are displayed here. The exquisite woodcarvings of CP Rajaram are displayed on the first floor. Other than this, there is the Hebbar Section dedicated to K.K. Hebbar to display his paintings.
        Timings: 10 AM to 5 PM. Closed on Wednesdays and public holidays.
    </string>

    <string name="hal">Situated on Old Airport Road, at the Hindustan Aeronautics Limited (HAL), the HAL Aerospace Museum is another popular place to visit in the city of Bangalore. It boasts of being the first aerospace Museum of India. Established in the year 2001, it has been attracting visitors since then. Tourists belonging to various age groups come here to understand the Indian Aviation industry.
        A part of the HAL Heritage Centre and Aero Space Museum, it provides visitors with information of the various developments in India aviation. It is managed as well as taken care by the HAL itself which is one of the leading aerospace companies of not just India but Asia.
        When you visit the Museum you will be greeted with not a range of aircrafts and helicopters but you will also be provided with a flying experience. Along with helicopters and aircrafts, it also has display of Aircraft engine models, Flight simulators, a mock Air Traffic Control Tower, etc. It also presents a history of Indian Aviation industry.
        What makes your visit to this aerospace museum is the panoramic view of the landing and take-off of various aircrafts. At the ATC tower which has been located on the top of the roof, you can get amazing views of flights. The flight simulators which are located in the center present tourists with an incomparable flying experience. It is a must visit for those who are interested in the subject of Aviation. However, even if you are not a fan of flying objects, you can be sure of having a few interesting moments here.
    </string>

    <string name="kemp">The name of the museum is after the founder of Bangalore city Yelahanka Chieftain Kempegowda and is situated on the first floor of Mayo Hall.
        The enticing glass floor with an 18th-century map that runs throughout is one of the enticing features of the museum and second being the fiberglass statue of Kempe Gowda in the center of the museum.
        It is an interesting place to visit for the archeology and history buffs as it exhibits paintings and statue of the time when Kempe Gowda actually initiated the foundation or the blueprint of the town, the four towers which marked the boundary of the city with various old names for the places which are recognized differently today.
        Location: Field Marshal Cariappa Rd, Shanthala Nagar, Ashok Nagar, Bengaluru, Karnataka 560001
        Best Time to Visit: Anytime during the day, avoid visiting on a weekend.
        Price: INR 50 for adults and INR 30 for students.
        Timings: Opens from 10 AM to 5 PM on all days of the week except Saturdays and Sundays.
        Average time required to visit the place: 1 to 2 hours.
        Distance from Kempe Gowda Bus stand: Approximately 7 KM.
    </string>
</resources>