<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Tour Guide</string>
    <string name="card_view_heading">View Heading</string>
    <string name="rating">3.1</string>

    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="adevnture">Adeventure</string>
    <string name="rating_number">3.1</string>
    <string name="descriptionHead">Description</string>
    <string name="balikal_ranganswamy_betta">At a distance of 75 km from Bangalore City Junction, 16 km from Kanakapura 112 km from Mysore, Bilikal Rangaswamy Betta is a hill near Kanakapura town. It is one of the highest hills in the area. It is also called as Bilikal Betta means white rocks. This is a good destination for short one day trekking from Bangalore and is one of the popular tourist places to visit near Bangalore city.
        Bilikal Rangaswamy Betta lies at an elevation of 3780 ft. There is a temple dedicated to Lord Rangaswamy at the peak of Bilikal Betta. This temple is located underneath a huge, white colored rock. The temple priest lives near to the temple and is the only person living at the peak. Every year, pilgrims from the surrounding area climb this hill to celebrate a festival at the Rangaswamy temple at the top.
        The Trekking Trail starts from Konala Doddi (which is about 58 kms from Bangalore City Junction - Bilikal Betta is 6 kms from here). Bilikal Rangaswamy Trek is a moderate one with a well marked path up till the peak. The trekking takes 2.5 hrs uphill and about 1.5 hr downhill. The trail begins with a half kilometer walk on a relatively level path, after which the forest becomes denser and the gradient of slope increases drastically. The trail constantly winds uphill at an incline and includes slightly steep stretches.
        Bilikal Rangaswamy Betta belongs to the Eastern Ghats and is filled with shrub forest. Elephants and other animals can be spotted in these forests during the night. The view from the top is very picturesque as one can see the hillocks from the surrounding Kanakapura range, mainly BM betta, Kabbala durga and Savanadurga too.
        Best time to visit Bilikal Rangaswamy Betta is during the post monsoon season of August to January. Hotels are available at Harohalli. No shops are available at Koonala Doddi and afterwards, so need to carry your own food and water.
        The trek starts from Konala Doddi, which about 6 kms from Bilikal Betta. KSRTC and private buses are available to Kanakapura from KR Market which passes through Harohalli (42 km from Bangalore City Junction). From Harohalli, KSRTC and private buses are available to Dodda Maralawadi (11 kms from Harohalli). From Dodda Maralawadi, very few transportation options are available to Konala Doddi (5 kms from Dodda Maralawadi), but autos or private vehicles can be hired. Private cabs are also available at Harohalli to Konala Doddi.
        Apart from the Trek route from Konala Doddi, there is jeep track till the peak from Kanakapura, which can also be trekked but a little long route.
</string>

    <string name="skandagiri">At a distance of 61 km from Bangalore City Junction and 5 km from Chikballapur, Skandagiri is an ancient mountain fortress lies at an altitude of about 1350 m. It is geographically located close to Nandi HIlls. This is among the best places for trekking near Bangalore especially famous for night treks, camping and bird watching.
        Skandagiri is also known as Kalavara Durga. It has an ancient dilapidated fort that belonged to a local king and was later concurred and used by Tipu Sultan. After Tipu\'s downfall, the fort was ignored and laid in ruins. Today one can only see parts of the fort wall in some places.
        The Skandagiri trek is a moderately difficult trek. There are two routes to reach the base of the hill. One is from Chikballapur town and the other as a detour from the road that leads to Nandi Hills. The trek starts from the Papagni Temple at the foot of the hill. This steep and fantastic trek through a maze of dense shrub is highly interesting. There are six series of stonewalls protecting an abandoned ancient temple on the hilltop.
        Skandagiri is more famous for night trekking. Hundreds of people gather there on Saturday and Sunday mornings to watch the sunrise. It is best climbed very early in the morning or in a full moon night. Sunrise seen from the top is breathtaking. At the top of the hill is a stretch of flat area that has a temple and few stone pillars belonging to ancient houses. This 8 km trek comprises of ascending and descending through rugged terrains and can be completed within 4-5 hours of ascending and descending.
        On the uphill trek you will encounter two caves. One is at the base of the hill and the other is on the midway - approximately thirty feet from the top. Trekkers must carry water, first aid box, snacks and torch. Local villagers camp on the peak and sell omelets, cold drinks, tea and other refreshments. They even gather wood for you in case you want a campfire and can serve as guides over the terrain.
        The best time to visit Skandagiri is from May to December.</string>

    <string name="kaigal_falls">At a distance of 2.5 km from Kaigal Village, 28 km from Palamaner, 55 km from Kolar, 92 km from Horsley Hills, 142 km from Tirupati, 123 km from Bangalore, 68 from Chittoor, 78 km from Kanipakam, 96 km from Vellore 225 km from Chennai, Kaigal Water Falls, also known as Dumukurallu Waterfalls is a nice waterfall located on the Palamaner - Kuppam Highway.
        The waterfall is natural, perennial and water comes from a big rock at a height of 40 feet, irrespective of seasons. But its force and beauty is increased during the Monsoon season. The name Dumukurallu waterfalls came into prominence because of its sound resembling the fall of stones from above.
        The falls is formed by the Kaigal stream which is one of the two streams flowing through Koundinya Wildlife Sanctuary. There is a big pond below the waterfalls and this is a nice place to visit for nature lovers. It is situated in a dense forest with plenty of birds, shrubs, trees and wildlife. The falls is particularly popular picnic destination for people from surrounding areas. There is a shivalinga installed near the falls which attracts pilgrims from nearby villages during Shivaratri festival.
        Visitors seeking public transportation can take Palamaner - Kuppam bus and get down at Kaigal waterfalls bus stop. From the Kaigal Waterfalls bus stop, the falls can be reached by 10 minute walk on mud road. The road from highway becomes inaccessible for vehicles during peak monsoons and walking is the best mode to reach the falls from main road.
        There is no accommodation available nearby waterfalls. Best season to visit the waterfalls is between September and December.</string>

    <string name="shiva_temple">At a distance of 2.5 km from Kaigal Village, 28 km from Palamaner, 55 km from Kolar, 92 km from Horsley Hills, 142 km from Tirupati, 123 km from Bangalore, 68 from Chittoor, 78 km from Kanipakam, 96 km from Vellore &amp; 225 km from Chennai, Kaigal Water Falls, also known as Dumukurallu Waterfalls is a nice waterfall located on the Palamaner - Kuppam Highway.
        The waterfall is natural, perennial and water comes from a big rock at a height of 40 feet, irrespective of seasons. But its force and beauty is increased during the Monsoon season. The name Dumukurallu waterfalls came into prominence because of its sound resembling the fall of stones from above.
        The falls is formed by the Kaigal stream which is one of the two streams flowing through Koundinya Wildlife Sanctuary. There is a big pond below the waterfalls and this is a nice place to visit for nature lovers. It is situated in a dense forest with plenty of birds, shrubs, trees and wildlife. The falls is particularly popular picnic destination for people from surrounding areas. There is a shivalinga installed near the falls which attracts pilgrims from nearby villages during Shivaratri festival.
        Visitors seeking public transportation can take Palamaner - Kuppam bus and get down at Kaigal waterfalls bus stop. From the Kaigal Waterfalls bus stop, the falls can be reached by 10 minute walk on mud road. The road from highway becomes inaccessible for vehicles during peak monsoons and walking is the best mode to reach the falls from main road.
        There is no accommodation available nearby waterfalls. Best season to visit the waterfalls is between September and December.</string>

    <string name="ulsoor_lake">At a distance of 7.5 Kms from Bangalore City Railway Station, Ulsoor Lake is a man-made lake located in Ulsoor. Spread across an area of 125 acres, it is one of the best places to visit in Bangalore city to spend a wonderful evening.
        Though the initial lake built during Kempe Gowda\'s time, it was enhanced by Sir Lewin Bentham Bowring, the then Commissioner of Bangalore. The lake has a recreational complex that has a swimming pool. There is also a garden at one end of the lake known as Kensington Park. This lake is a center of attraction during Ganesh Chathurdi.
        Boating facilities are available in Ulsoor Lake. There are many small islands spread across the lake and they can be reached by boat. The Boat Club maintained by KSTDC offers wonderful boating facilities. The boating fee is Rs 120 per hour.
        Timings: 9:30 AM to 5:30 PM on all days.</string>

    <string name="hesarghatta_lake">At a distance of 21 Kms from Bangalore City Railway Station, the Hesaraghatta Lake is a man made fresh water reservoir spread over an area of 1620 hectares. The lake among very good points of interest in Bangalore for bird watching.
        Constructed across Arkavathy River, the lake has been the source of drinking water to Bangalore city since 1896. The lake was planned by the then chief engineer of Mysore MC Hutchins and the Dewan Sir K Seshadri with the plan to supply drinking water to the city.
        The spot is also known for research and development farms for poultry, animal husbandry, agriculture and horticulture. Birds like kingfisher, magpie robin, little egrets, common mynas, Brahminy kites, black drangos, bulbuls, greater coucals, purple sunbirds, etc., have been reported in and around the lake periphery.
        Boating and windsurfing are the main attractions of the lake.</string>
</resources>
